<resources>

    <string name="app_name">SPb Tour Guide</string>

    <!-- Category -->
    <string name="category_museums">MUSEUMS</string>
    <string name="category_theatres">THEATRES</string>
    <string name="category_parks">PARKS</string>
    <string name="category_sports">SPORTS</string>

    <string name="sight_image">Sight image</string>

    <!-- MUSEUMS -->
    <!-- Hermitage -->
    <string name="hermitage_name">Hermitage</string>
    <string name="hermitage_description">The State Hermitage Museum is a museum of art and culture in Saint Petersburg, Russia. The second-largest in the world, it was founded in 1764 when Empress Catherine the Great acquired an impressive collection of paintings from the Berlin merchant Johann Ernst Gotzkowsky. The museum celebrates the anniversary of its founding each year on 7 December, Saint Catherine\'s Day. It has been open to the public since 1852.</string>
    <string name="hermitage_link">https://www.hermitagemuseum.org/</string>
    <!-- Russian museum -->
    <string name="russian_name">Russian Museum</string>
    <string name="russian_description">The State Russian Museum, formerly the Russian Museum of His Imperial Majesty Alexander III, is the largest depository of Russian fine art in Saint Petersburg. It is also one of the largest museums in the country. The museum was established on April 13, 1895, upon enthronement of Nicholas II to commemorate his father, Alexander III. Its original collection was composed of artworks taken from the Hermitage Museum, Alexander Palace, and the Imperial Academy of Arts. After the Russian Revolution of 1917, many private collections were nationalized and relocated to the Russian Museum. These included Kazimir Malevich\'s Black Square.</string>
    <string name="russian_link">http://en.rusmuseum.ru/</string>
    <!-- Erarta -->
    <string name="erarta_name">Erarta</string>
    <string name="erarta_description">Erarta is the largest private museum of contemporary art in Russia. In the museum, visitors are welcome to book guided tours, individual or group ones. They may also rent an audio-guide at the registration desk on first floor. There are special themes and gaming excursions for schoolchildren. On 30 June 2015, the collection of Erarta Museum of Contemporary Art became digitally available via the Google Cultural Institute\’s Art Project.</string>
    <string name="erarta_link">https://www.erarta.com/en/</string>
    <!-- Isaak's -->
    <string name="isaak_name">Saint Isaac\'s Cathedral</string>
    <string name="isaak_description">Saint Isaac\'s Cathedral or Isaakievskiy Sobor is the largest Russian Orthodox cathedral (sobor) in the city. It is the largest orthodox basilica and the fourth largest (by the volume under the cupola) cathedral in the world. It is dedicated to Saint Isaac of Dalmatia, a patron saint of Peter the Great, who had been born on the feast day of that saint.</string>
    <string name="isaak_link">http://eng.cathedral.ru/</string>
    <!-- Peter & Pavel -->
    <string name="fortress_name">Peter and Paul Fortress</string>
    <string name="fortress_description">The Peter and Paul Fortress is the original citadel of St. Petersburg, Russia, founded by Peter the Great in 1703 and built to Domenico Trezzini\'s designs from 1706 to 1740 as a star fortress. In the early 1920s, it was still used as a prison and execution ground by the Bolshevik government. Today it has been adapted as the central and most important part of the State Museum of Saint Petersburg History. The museum has gradually become virtually the sole owner of the fortress building, except the structure occupied by the Saint Petersburg Mint (Monetniy Dvor).</string>
    <string name="fortress_link">http://www.spbmuseum.ru/themuseum/museum_complex/peterpaul_fortress/?lang_ui=en</string>

    <!-- THEATRES -->
    <!-- Mikhailovsky -->
    <string name="mikhailovsky_name">Mikhailovsky Theatre</string>
    <string name="mikhailovsky_description">In 2001, the Mikhailovsky Theatre reclaimed its historic name, and in 2007, it was recognized as St. Petersburg\’s most prestigious musical theatre. Today, while preserving Russia\’s centuries-old musical theatre traditions, the Mikhailovsky Theatre is constantly pushing to be at the forefront of contemporary world theatre. The renovated luxury of the entrance hall and auditorium enables theatre lovers to pass their time in comfort.</string>
    <string name="mikhailovsky_link">https://mikhailovsky.ru/en/</string>
    <!-- Mariinsky -->
    <string name="mariinsky_name">Mariinsky Theatre</string>
    <string name="mariinsky_description">The Mariinsky Theatre is a historic theatre of opera and ballet in Saint Petersburg, Russia. Opened in 1860, it became the preeminent music theatre of late 19th-century Russia, where many of the stage masterpieces of Tchaikovsky, Mussorgsky, and Rimsky-Korsakov received their premieres. Through most of the Soviet era, it was known as the Kirov Theatre. Today, the Mariinsky Theatre is home to the Mariinsky Ballet, Mariinsky Opera and Mariinsky Orchestra. Since Yuri Temirkanov\'s retirement in 1988, the conductor Valery Gergiev has served as the theatre\'s general director.</string>
    <string name="mariinsky_link">https://www.mariinsky.ru/en/</string>
    <!-- BDT -->
    <string name="bdt_name">Bolshoi Drama Theatre</string>
    <string name="bdt_description">Tovstonogov Bolshoi Drama Theatre, formerly known as Gorky Bolshoi Drama Theatre (1931–1992), often referred to as the Bolshoi Drama Theatre and by the acronym BDT, is a theatre in Saint Petersburg, that is considered one of the best Russian theatres. The theatre is named after its long-time director Georgy Tovstonogov. Since 2013, Andrey Moguchy is the artistic director of the theatre.</string>
    <string name="bdt_link">https://bdt.spb.ru/</string>
    <!-- Philharmonic Hall -->
    <string name="philharmonic_name">Philharmonic Hall</string>
    <string name="philharmonic_description">The St. Petersburg Philharmonia, the oldest Philharmonia in Russia, is more than two hundred years old. Its history goes back to 1802 when the St. Petersburg Philharmonic Society, the first one in Europe, was created. It organized the world premiere of Beethoven\'s Missa Solemnis in 1824.</string>
    <string name="philharmonic_link">http://www.philharmonia.spb.ru/en/</string>
    <!-- TYZ -->
    <string name="tyz_name">The Youth Theatre </string>
    <string name="tyz_description">The A. Bryantsev Youth Theatre (also spelled State Theater For Young Audience Named After A. A. Bryantsev or Bryantsev Young Viewers Theater) is one of the first professional children\'s theatres in Russia, opened in 1922. In Soviet time the theatre was called Leningrad Young People\'s Theatre. In 1962 it was moved to the current newly constructed building. The theatre is in Saint Petersburg, on the Pionerskaya Square near the end of Gorokhovaya Street.</string>
    <string name="tyz_link">http://www.tyuz-spb.ru/</string>

    <!-- Parks -->
    <!-- Summer Garden -->
    <string name="summer_name">Summer Garden</string>
    <string name="summer_description">The Summer Garden occupies an island between the Fontanka, Moika, and the Swan Canal and shares its name with the adjacent Summer Palace of Peter the Great. The park was personally designed by Czar Peter in 1704, supposedly, with the assistance of the Dutch gardener and physician Nicolaas Bidloo. Starting from 1712, the planting of the Summer Garden was further elaborated by the Dutch gardener Jan Roosen, who was the chief gardener of the park till 1726. The well-known French architect Jean-Baptiste Le Blond, who arrived in St. Petersburg in 1716, added to the park the flavour of a Garden à la française. The Summer Garden was largely completed in 1719. The walks were lined with a hundred allegorical marble sculptures, executed by Francesco Penso, Pietro Baratta, Marino Gropelli, Alvise Tagliapietra, Bartolomeo Modulo and other Venetian sculptors that were acquired by Sava Vladislavich.</string>
    <string name="summer_link">http://en.rusmuseum.ru/summer-garden/history/</string>
    <!-- Peterhof -->
    <string name="peterhof_name">Peterhof</string>
    <string name="peterhof_description">After 200 years of serving as a grand summer residence of the emperors, Peterhof is inextricably connected with the Russian history. The seaside paradise was built, as a grandiose triumphal memorial glorifying the grandeur of Russia, in conquering the much needed and desired access to the Baltic Sea, during the Great Northern War. Building date: 1714&#8211;1723. Architects: I. Braunstein, J.B. Le Blond, N. Miketti, F. Rastrelli, A.N. Voronikhin, A.I. Stackenschneider, L. Harnigfelt, А. Borisov, B. Fok, Т. Timofeev.</string>
    <string name="peterhof_link">https://en.peterhofmuseum.ru/</string>
    <!-- Tzar -->
    <string name="tzar_name">The Tsarskoe Selo</string>
    <string name="tzar_description">Tsarskoye Selo (\"Tsar\'s Village\") was the town containing a former Russian residence of the imperial family and visiting nobility, located 24 kilometers (15 mi) south from the center of Saint Petersburg. Tsarskoye Selo forms one of the World Heritage Site Saint Petersburg and Related Groups of Monuments. In the 17th century, the estate belonged to a Swedish noble. Max Vasmer, on the other hand, derives this toponym from the Finnish word for island, "\saari\": "\Saaren kylä\" = "\Island village\". By the 18th-century at the latest, it was called "\Tsarskoye Selo\". In 1708, Peter the Great gave the estate to his wife, the future Empress Catherine I, as a present.</string>
    <string name="tzar_link">http://eng.tzar.ru/</string>
    <!-- Pavlovsk -->
    <string name="pavlovsk_name">Pavlovsk</string>
    <string name="pavlovsk_description">Among the palace-and-park ensembles encircling Petersburg in a green belt, the Pavlovsk complex of landscape combined with architecture was the latest to come into being. This is an outstanding landmark of the Russian culture of the late 18th - early 19th century. Work commenced on the grounds in 1777 to implement the project of a country house for Grand Duke Paul, the son of Catherine II, who was later crowned as Emperor Paul I. Outstanding architects, sculptors and artists were commissioned to lay out a huge park covering about 600 hectares and build the Palace and park structures. Their concepts were brought to life by landscape architects, gardeners and hundreds of workmen and peasants from local villages.</string>
    <string name="pavlovsk_link">http://en.pavlovskmuseum.ru/</string>
    <!-- Gatchina -->
    <string name="gatchina_name">Gatchina</string>
    <string name="gatchina_description">The Gatchina Palace and park is one of Russia\’s outstanding ensembles. With its own unique identity, it is just another gem in the ring of imperial suburban palaces around St Petersburg. The Gatchina parks are famous not only for its architectural and historical structures, but also for its unparalleled natural beauty. The variety of animals and plants here is amazing. The most common animals living in the park are squirrels, moles, field mice, bats and water birds.</string>
    <string name="gatchina_link">http://gatchinapalace.ru/en/</string>
</resources>
